<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Submitting Jobs on Lane Cluster Documentation</title><link>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/</link><description>Recent content in Submitting Jobs on Lane Cluster Documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Simple sbatch Script</title><link>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/simple-script/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/simple-script/</guid><description>Consider the following shell script.
#!/bin/bash # contents of example_script.sh seq 1 10000 | shuf | sort -n This prints numbers from 1 to 10000 (seq), randomly shuffles them (shuf), then attempts to resort them. How could we submit this as a job? The simplest answer is to just execute sbatch with this script as a parameter.
sbatch -p pool1 -n 1 example_script.sh This will request one task (-n 1) on the pool1 partition (-p pool1) and run our script on it.</description></item><item><title>Useful sbatch Flags</title><link>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/useful-flags/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/useful-flags/</guid><description>In the following table X is an integer and S is a string.
Flag Value Format Description -p S Partition that job should be submitted to. Can be a comma-separated list if you aren&amp;rsquo;t concerned with forcing a particular partition -n X Number of concurrent tasks you will run for this job. Tasks can be allocated from within your job script with srun -c X Number of CPUs each task will use for this job --mem-per-cpu X[KMGT] for KB,MB,GB,TB respectively Amount of memory per CPU this job requires --mem X[KMGT] for KB,MB,GB,TB respectively Amount of memory this job requires total, not per CPU -t X-XX:XX:XX Sets a maximum running time for your job.</description></item><item><title>Array Jobs</title><link>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/array-jobs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/array-jobs/</guid><description>What if I want to perform the same computation on a very large number of inputs? The Slurm solution to this is an array job. An array job executes the same script many times. It is specified with the sbatch flag -a. For each integer value of -a Slurm will create a distinct job and within that job set the environment variable SLURM_ARRAY_TASK_ID to the associated value of -a.
Example -a Explanation -a 1-100 Run an array job with array values 1,2,3,&amp;hellip;,100 -a 100-200 Run an array job with array values 100,102,103,&amp;hellip;,200 -a 0-15:4 Run an array job with array values 0,4,8,12 -a 0-15:2 Run an array job with array values 0,2,4,6,8,10,12,14 -a 0-15%2 Run an array job with array values 0,1,2,3,&amp;hellip;,15 but only ever have 2 running simultaneously There are limitations to array jobs.</description></item><item><title>Job Dependencies</title><link>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/job-dependencies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/job-dependencies/</guid><description>You may end up wanting to have jobs wait for other jobs before they execute, either to guarantee some preprocessing or conserve cluster resources. This can be accomplished with the -d flag of sbatch. The -d flag takes values of the format type:job_id.
-d Type Explanation after After job ID has begun, not ended afterany After job ID has finished, regardless of error status afterok After job ID has finished and has not exited with an error afternotok After job ID has finished and has exited with an error aftercorr After array task of job ID corresponding with this array job&amp;rsquo;s array task has finished successfully.</description></item><item><title>sbatch vs srun</title><link>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/sbatch-vs-srun/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mguler.github.io/lane_cluster/slurm-basics/submitting-jobs/sbatch-vs-srun/</guid><description>These two commands take almost the exact same parameters. The difference is sbatch submits jobs to the Slurm scheduler, to be run when requested resources become available. Running the same job directly with srun will actually run synchronously. In other words, you will have to sit and wait while the job runs and logging out of the cluster will likely terminate your job. It is generally not recommended to directly execute jobs with srun, one exception can be see in Interactive Sessions</description></item></channel></rss>